Guide to the Arthur A. Allen papers,1899-1968,
Allen, Arthur A. papers,1899-1968,
- Series IV. Organizations
  - Membership Cards, 1913-1964 (Box 120, Folder 48)
- Series V. Wildlife Refuge Creation
  - Conservation of Wildlife, 1928-1940 (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - The Wildlife Society, 1938-1940 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Montezuma National Wildlife Refuge, 1951 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - Creation of Wildlife Refuge, 1961 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Creation of Wildlife Refuge, 1961 (Box 121, Folder 5)
  - Conservation of Wildlife, 1924-1925 (Box 121, Folder 6)
  - Dunham Bird Collection, 1882-1885 (Box 121, Folder 7)
  - Connecticut Hill Game Refuge, 1927 (Box 121, Folder 8)
  - Connecticut Hill Game Refuge, 1927 (Box 121, Folder 9)
  - "Game Refuges, Public Shooting Grounds and the Utilization of Non-Agricultural Lands", 1927 (Box 121, Folder 10)
  - "The Demonstration of Forest Idea"; "The Conservation Fund on New York State";"The Forest Survey", undated (Box 121, Folder 11)
  - Connecticut Hill Game Refuge, undated (Box 121, Folder 12)
  - "The Wild Plants of Connecticut Hill", 1927 (Box 121, Folder 13)
  - Glenside Farm, 1917-1930 (Box 121, Folder 14)
  - Glenside Farm, 1917-1930 (Box 121, Folder 15)
  - Bird Sanctuaries, 1924 (Box 121, Folder 16)
  - "Gold Clubs as Bird Sanctuaries", 1930 (Box 121, Folder 17)
  - "Gold Clubs as Bird Sanctuaries", 1930 (Box 121, Folder 18)
  - Bird Protection and Migration Patterns, 1923-1926 (Box 121, Folder 19)
  - "Support of the Alaska Eagle Bounty", 1924 (Box 121, Folder 20)
  - Sapsucker Woods Correspondence, 1944-1952 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Sapsucker Woods Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - Sapsucker Woods - Preliminary Sketches, 1956 (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - Sapsucker Woods - Council Meetings, 1962 (Box 122, Folder 4)
  - "Sapsucker Woods Story", 1962 (Box 122, Folder 5)
  - Sapsucker Woods - Dedication, 1965 (Box 122, Folder 6)
  - Sapsucker Woods - Dedication Ceremonies, 1956-1965 (Box 122, Folder 7)
  - Sapsucker Woods, 1963 (Box 122, Folder 8)
  - Sapsucker Woods - Laboratory of Ornithology Publications, 1966 (Box 122, Folder 9)
  - "Bring Them Back to Life", undated (Box 122, Folder 10)
  - "Spring Thunder in Sapsucker Woods", undated (Box 122, Folder 11)
  - Sapsucker Woods - Business Affairs, 1952-1965 (Box 122, Folder 12)
  - "Cornell University's Exciting New Bird Sanctuary", 1962 (Box 122, Folder 13)
- Series VI. Manuscripts and Reprints by Arthur Allen
  - By Title: A-G
    - "From Bonds to Birds", 1936 (Box 122, Folder 14)
    - "Ambassadors of Good Will", 1942 (Box 122, Folder 15)
    - "Another Year", 1923 (Box 122, Folder 16)
    - "An Arizona Nest of the Coppery-tailed Trogon", 1944 (Box 122, Folder 17)
    - "Attracting the Winter Birds", 1915 (Box 122, Folder 18)
    - "The Autobiography of a Mother Grouse", 1927 (Box 122, Folder 19)
    - "The Autobiography of Jim Crow", 1928 (Box 122, Folder 20)
    - "Autumn Birds and their Message", 1916 (Box 122, Folder 21)
    - "The Avocet and Other Shore-birds at Ithaca During the Fall of 1909", 1910 (Box 122, Folder 22)
    - "Banding Bats", 1921 (Box 122, Folder 23)
    - "The Bank Swallow Story", 1933 (Box 122, Folder 24)
    - "Bug Thompson of the Swamp River", 1915 (Box 122, Folder 25)
    - "Bird in the Schoolroom", 1921 (Box 122, Folder 26)
    - "Birds", 1956 (Box 122, Folder 27)
    - "Bird Photography in Sapsucker Woods", 1963 (Box 122, Folder 28)
    - "Bird", 1956 (Box 122, Folder 29)
    - Birds and Bird Lore - Manuscript, 1924 (Box 122, Folder 30-37)
    - Birds and Bird Lore - Draft, 1924 (Box 122, Folder 38-49)
    - Birds, Bird Lore and Animal Life, 1924 (Box 122, Folder 50)
    - "Birds and the Camera", 1917 (Box 122, Folder 51)
    - "Birds and the Forest", 1915 (Box 122, Folder 52)
    - "Birds and Trees in Winter", 1920 (Box 122, Folder 53)
    - "Birds and their Relation to Agriculture", 1914 (Box 122, Folder 54)
    - "Birds' Nest", 1919 (Box 122, Folder 55)
    - "Birds' Nest and How to Find Them", 1925 (Box 122, Folder 56)
    - "Birds of the Woodland Borders", 1925 (Box 122, Folder 57)
    - "Birds of the Timberline and Tundra", 1946 (Box 122, Folder 58)
    - "Birds on the Home Front", 1942 (Box 122, Folder 59)
    - "The Bird's Year", 1951 (Box 122, Folder 60)
    - "Blackbirds and Orioles", 1934 (Box 122, Folder 61)
    - "Black Water Dave", 1916 (Box 122, Folder 62)
    - Book of Bird Life, 1961 (Box 122, Folder 63-65)
      Draft
    - Book of Bird Life, 1961 (Box 122, Folder 66)
      Proof Notes
    - Book of Bird Life, 1961 (Box 122, Folder 67)
      Book, proof
    - Obituary for Albert R. Brand, 1941 (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - "Bringing Back the Game", 1917 (Box 123, Folder 2)
    - "The Cayuga Bird Club", undated (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - "Cherry Bird: The Cedar Waxwing", 1930 (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - "A Christmas Walk with Birds and Beasts", 1919 (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - "Christmas with the Birds", 1918 (Box 123, Folder 6)
    - "Cock Robin: His Story", 1928 (Box 123, Folder 7)
    - "Collier's Encyclopedia" - Articles on Birds, 1960 (Box 123, Folder 8)
    - The Coloration of Birds", 1916 (Box 123, Folder 9)
    - "Conserving the Waterfowl", 1915 (Box 123, Folder 10)
    - "A Contribution to the Life History and Economic Status of the Screech Owl", 1924 (Box 123, Folder 11)
    - "Cooperation", 1920 (Box 123, Folder 12)
    - "Cory's Last Bittern in Ithaca, NY", 1913 (Box 123, Folder 13)
    - "The Crested Flycatcher's Story", 1933 (Box 123, Folder 14)
    - "The Cuckoos", 1918 (Box 123, Folder 15)
    - The Curlew's Secret", 1948 (Box 123, Folder 16)
    - "Dame Orioles Story", 1928 (Box 123, Folder 17)
    - "A Day with the Ducks on Lake Cayuga", 1920 (Box 123, Folder 18)
    - "Diurnal Birds of Prey", 1918 (Box 123, Folder 19)
    - "Downy Woodpecker's Story", 1928 (Box 123, Folder 20)
    - "The Duck Hawks of Taughannock Gorge", 1913 (Box 123, Folder 21)
    - " Duck Hunting with a Camera", 1951 (Box 123, Folder 22)
    - "The Eggs and Young of the Bristle-thighed Curlew", 1949 (Box 123, Folder 23)
    - "The Enemies of Birds", 1916 (Box 123, Folder 24)
    - "Federal Protection of Birds", 1916 (Box 123, Folder 25)
    - " Fight or Flight", 1957 (Box 123, Folder 26)
    - "The Finches", undated (Box 123, Folder 27)
    - "The Flicker's Story", 1933 (Box 123, Folder 28)
    - The Friendly Chippy", 1929 (Box 123, Folder 29)
    - "Louis Agassiz Fuertes", 1957 (Box 123, Folder 30)
    - "Louis Agassiz Fuertes, Bird Artist", 1918 (Box 123, Folder 31)
    - "Function of the College in the Field of Ornithology", 1925 (Box 123, Folder 32)
    - "Game Birds as Pets", 1920 (Box 123, Folder 33)
    - "The Golden Plover", undated (Box 123, Folder 34)
    - "The Gulls and Terns", 1919 (Box 123, Folder 35)
  - By Title: H-N
    - "The Hell Diver's Story", 1930 (Box 123, Folder 36)
    - "The Herons", 1919 (Box 123, Folder 37)
    - "How to Attract Summer Birds - Bird Houses", 1916 (Box 123, Folder 38)
    - "The Hummingbirds and Swifts", 1918 (Box 123, Folder 39)
    - "Hunting with a Microphone", 1937 (Box 123, Folder 40)
    - "The Implements of Birds", 1916 (Box 123, Folder 41)
    - "Increase of Austral Birds at Ithaca", 1910 (Box 123, Folder 42)
    - "The Indigo Bunting", 1910 (Box 123, Folder 43)
    - "Key to the Orders and Families of North American Birds", 1922-1925 (Box 123, Folder 44)
    - "The Kingfishers", 1918 (Box 123, Folder 45)
    - "Life of the Ruby-throated Hummingbird", undated (Box 123, Folder 46)
    - "Life of the Ruby-throated Hummingbird", 1952 (Box 123, Folder 47)
    - The Loons and Grebes", 1919 (Box 123, Folder 48)
    - "Making Friends with the Birds", 1917 (Box 123, Folder 49)
    - "Management Programs Controls Starlings", 1946 (Box 123, Folder 50)
    - George M. McNeil Obituary, 1932 (Box 123, Folder 51)
    - "The Mockingbird Family", 1917 (Box 123, Folder 52)
    - "Moving Pictures of Canvasbacks", 1915 (Box 123, Folder 53)
    - "Nest-building and Egg Laying", 1929 (Box 123, Folder 54)
    - "The Nesting of Birds", 1916 (Box 123, Folder 55)
    - "A New Bird for North America", 1934 (Box 123, Folder 56)
    - "The New Natural History", undated (Box 123, Folder 57)
    - "Night Hawks and Whip-poor-wills", 1918 (Box 123, Folder 58)
    - "The Nighthawks Story", 1933 (Box 123, Folder 59)
    - "The Nuthatch", 1929 (Box 123, Folder 60)
    - "Nuthatches and Chickadees", 1917 (Box 123, Folder 61)
  - By Title: O-Z
    - "The Origins of Birds", 1927 (Box 123, Folder 62)
    - "Ornithologists Education in America 1883-1933", 1934 (Box 123, Folder 63)
    - "Ornithology at Cornell", undated (Box 123, Folder 64)
    - "Our Vanishing Shorebirds", 1915 (Box 123, Folder 65)
    - "Our Winter Birds and What They do for us", 1916 (Box 123, Folder 66)
    - "The Owls", 1918 (Box 123, Folder 67)
    - "The Paramo of Santa Isabel", 1915 (Box 123, Folder 68)
    - "The Passing of a Great Teacher", 1927 (Box 123, Folder 69)
      Regarding Louis Agassiz Fuertes
    - "Perpetuates Bird Sanctuary", 1956 (Box 123, Folder 70)
    - "Photography and Ornithology", 1918 (Box 123, Folder 71)
    - "The Pigeons and Doves", 1918 (Box 123, Folder 72)
    - "Planting to Attract Birds", 1916 (Box 123, Folder 73)
    - "The Plovers", 1919 (Box 123, Folder 74)
    - "Rails, Gallinules, and Coots", 1919 (Box 123, Folder 75)
    - "Recent Observations of the Ivory-billed Woodpecker", 1937 (Box 123, Folder 76)
    - "Recording the Timber Doodle", 1949 (Box 123, Folder 77)
    - "The Red-winged Blackbird. A Study in the Ecology of a Cattail Marsh", 1911 (Box 123, Folder 78)
    - "The Redwing", undated (Box 123, Folder 79)
    - "The Return of the Birds", 1916 (Box 123, Folder 80)
    - "Ring Out the Old", undated (Box 123, Folder 81)
    - "The Sandpipers", 1919 (Box 123, Folder 82)
    - "Sapsucker Woods", 1956 (Box 123, Folder 83)
    - "Sapsucker Woods. Cornell University's Exciting New Bird Sanctuary", 1962 (Box 123, Folder 84)
    - "Sapsucker Woods, Revisited", undated (Box 123, Folder 85)
    - "Windows of Sapsucker Woods", 1958 (Box 123, Folder 86)
    - "Sea Birds Cities Off Audubon's Labrador", 1948 (Box 123, Folder 87)
    - "The Season of Courtship", undated (Box 123, Folder 88)
    - "Sex Rhythm in the Ruffled Grouse and Other Birds", 1934 (Box 123, Folder 89)
    - "Sights and Sounds of the Winged World", 1945 (Box 123, Folder 90)
    - "Some Changes in the Bird life of Churchill, Manitoba, 1945 (Box 123, Folder 91)
    - "Some Familiar Bird Friends", 1918 (Box 123, Folder 92)
    - "Some Problems with Everyday Birds", 1916 (Box 123, Folder 93)
    - "Split Seconds in the Life of Birds", 1954 (Box 123, Folder 94)
    - "Spring on the Marshes", 1920 (Box 123, Folder 95)
    - "Stalking Birds with a Color Camera", 1939 and 1951 (Box 123, Folder 96)
    - "Stalking Birds with a Color Camera", 1939 and 1951 (Box 123, Folder 97)
    - "Stalking Birds with a Color Camera", 1951 (Box 123, Folder 98)
    - "Stalking Birds with a Color Camera", 1951 and 1952 (Box 123, Folder 99)
    - "The Starling", undated (Box 124, Folder 1)
    - "The Strange Mother", 1928 (Box 124, Folder 2)
    - "The Study of Birds", 1924 (Box 124, Folder 3)
    - "Studying Birds Eggs", 1920 (Box 124, Folder 4)
    - Studying Ptarmigan at Hudson Bay", 1934 (Box 124, Folder 5)
    - "Summer and Winter Ranges of North American Birds", 1933 (Box 124, Folder 6)
    - "A Summer with a Hummer", 1931 (Box 124, Folder 7)
    - "They Said I was Drowned in the Gulf of Mexico", 1925 (Box 124, Folder 8)
    - "The Thrushes", 1917 (Box 124, Folder 9)
    - "Touring for Birds with a Microphone and a Color Camera", 1944 (Box 124, Folder 10)
    - "The Tree Sparrows", 1934 (Box 124, Folder 11)
    - "The True Hawks", 1918 (Box 124, Folder 12)
    - "Upland Game Birds", 1918 (Box 124, Folder 13)
      Grouse
    - "Upland Game Birds", 1918 (Box 124, Folder 14)
      Turkey, Quail and Pheasant
    - "Using One's Ear Out of Doors", 1940 (Box 124, Folder 15)
    - "Vacationing with Birds", 1940 (Box 124, Folder 16)
    - "Veery and his Family", 1933 (Box 124, Folder 17)
    - "The Vieros", 1917 (Box 124, Folder 18)
    - "The Virginia Rail and the Sora", 1934 (Box 124, Folder 19)
    - "Voices of the Night", 1950 (Box 124, Folder 20)
    - "The Warblers", 1917 (Box 124, Folder 21)
    - "The Warblers of Central New York", 1919 (Box 124, Folder 22)
    - "The Waterfowl", 1919 (Box 124, Folder 23)
    - "The Waxwing Family", 1917 (Box 124, Folder 24)
    - "What is a Game Bird", 1916 (Box 124, Folder 25)
    - "When the Northwind Blows", 1919 (Box 124, Folder 26)
    - "Where are the Summer Birds at Christmas?", 1925 (Box 124, Folder 27)
    - "The Widow Ptarmigan", 1935 (Box 124, Folder 28)
    - "Winter Bird Nests", 1920 (Box 124, Folder 29)
    - "Woodchuck in New York State", 1925 (Box 124, Folder 30)
    - "The Woodpeckers", 1917 (Box 124, Folder 31)
    - "The Wrens", 1917 (Box 124, Folder 32)
    - "Zonal Distribution of Mammals of the Region about Ithaca, New York", 1908 (Box 124, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Glossary, undated (Box 124, Folder 34-43)
    - Manuscript I, undated (Box 124, Folder 44)
    - Manuscript II, undated (Box 124, Folder 45)
    - "Evolution and Significance of Sex, Dimorphism and Hybridization in Birds and other Animals, 1957 (Box 124, Folder 46)
      Humorous
    - Reviews, undated (Box 124, Folder 47)
- Series VII. Teaching and Cornell University
  - Course Outlines and Lecture Notes
    - Courses, 1912-1914 (Box 124, Folder 48)
    - Research, 1921-1922 (Box 124, Folder 49)
    - Courses, 1925-1927 (Box 124, Folder 50)
    - Courses, 1927 (Box 124, Folder 51-52)
    - Courses, undated (Box 124, Folder 53)
    - Courses, 1936 (Box 124, Folder 54)
    - Ornithological References, 1939 (Box 124, Folder 55)
    - Courses, undated (Box 124, Folder 56)
    - Courses, 1938 (Box 124, Folder 57)
    - "Family Tree of Birds", undated (Box 124, Folder 58)
    - Courses, 1923 (Box 124, Folder 59)
    - Ornithology 126, 1940-1941 (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - Course Notebook, undated (Box 125, Folder 2)
    - Ornithology 126 - Examination, undated (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - General Ornithology, undated (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - "The Order of Birds", undated (Box 125, Folder 5)
    - Ornithology 126 - Examination, undated (Box 125, Folder 6)
    - Ornithology 126, undated (Box 125, Folder 7)
    - Student Work, undated (Box 125, Folder 8)
    - Aristotle to Fuertes, undated (Box 125, Folder 9)
    - Lectures, undated (Box 125, Folder 10)
    - "Key to the Families of Birds of this World", undated (Box 125, Folder 11)
    - "Taxonomy of Birds", undated (Box 125, Folder 12-13)
    - Courses, undated (Box 125, Folder 14)
    - Courses, 1937 (Box 125, Folder 15)
    - Lectures, 1928-1933 (Box 125, Folder 16)
    - Conservation of Wildlife, 1920-1924 (Box 125, Folder 17)
    - Wildlife Conservation and Game Farming Course, 1924 (Box 125, Folder 18)
    - Conservation of Wildlife, 1925-1931 (Box 125, Folder 19)
    - Conservation of Wildlife, 1933-1939 (Box 125, Folder 20)
    - Wildlife Conservation, 1940 (Box 125, Folder 21)
    - Conservation of Wildlife, 1946-1947 (Box 125, Folder 22)
    - Conservation of Wildlife, 1934 (Box 125, Folder 23)
    - Conservation of Wildlife, 1943-1945 (Box 125, Folder 24)
    - Conservation of Wildlife, 1946-1947 (Box 125, Folder 25)
    - "A Winter Survey of Wildlife Populations on a Forest Stand Improved Area", 1938 (Box 125, Folder 26)
    - Wildlife Conservation and Game Farming Course, 1920-1922 (Box 125, Folder 27-29)
    - Game Farm Expenses, 1925 (Box 125, Folder 30)
    - Extension Work - Courses, 1916-1933 (Box 125, Folder 31)
    - Birds and their Relation to Agriculture", 1924 (Box 125, Folder 32)
    - Class Roll Books, 1921-1952 (Box 126)
    - Game Management, 1938 (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - Game Management, 1940-1944 (Box 127, Folder 2)
    - Game Management II, 1936-1939 (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - College of Agriculture Related Records
    - Report on Wildlife Conservation and Management at New York State College of Agriculture, 1936-1938 (Box 127, Folder 4)
    - Entomology State Project: Numbers 47-56, 1936-1938 (Box 127, Folder 5-6)
    - Extension Reports, 1939-1940 (Box 127, Folder 7)
    - Department Organization, 1935 (Box 127, Folder 8)
    - Annual Inventory, 1932-1943 (Box 127, Folder 9)
    - Financial Statements, 1939-1943 (Box 127, Folder 10)
    - Development Report, 1939-1941 (Box 127, Folder 11)
    - Department Organization, 1944-1945 (Box 127, Folder 12-13)
    - Information Requests, 1941-1943 (Box 128, Folder 1-3)
    - Student Lists, 1922-1946 (Box 128, Folder 4)
    - Prospective Students, 1935 (Box 128, Folder 5)
    - Applicants for graduate study positions, 1938 (Box 128, Folder 6)
    - Prospective Students, 1946 (Box 128, Folder 7)
    - Placement Information, 1939 (Box 128, Folder 8)
    - Savage Club of Ithaca, NY, undated (Box 128, Folder 9)
    - Undergraduate Student Records A-K, 1934-1952 (Box 167)
    - Undergraduate Student Records M-Z, 1934-1952 (Box 168)
    - Graduate Student Records A-H, 1940-1952 (Box 169)
    - Graduate Student Records J-Z, 1934-1952 (Box 170)
    - Student Records, 1936-1952 (Box 171)
    - Graduate Student Records, 1937-1952 (Box 172)
    - Student Records, 1940-1952 (Box 173)
- Series VIII. Radio Talks
  - Radio Talks, 1937-1940 (Box 128, Folder 10-13)
  - Radio Talks - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 128, Folder 14-15)
- Series IX. Papers and Reprints by Others
  - By Last Name of Author: A-D
    - Reverend Noel J. Allen, undated (Box 129, Folder 1)
    - "The Auklet", 1924 (Box 129, Folder 2)
    - "The Song of the Kirkland's Warbler" by Harold J. Axtell, Jul-38 (Box 129, Folder 3)
    - "Neues zum Hummel problem", 1925 (Box 129, Folder 4)
    - Guy A. Bailey - 4 reprints, Oct-16 (Box 129, Folder 5)
    - Annual Cycle, Environment, and Evolution in the Hawaian Honeycreepers, 1953 (Box 129, Folder 6)
    - "Breeding Behavior of the Ring-necked pheasant on the Pelee Island, Ontario", 1950 (Box 129, Folder 7)
    - "Nesting of the Ring-necked Pheasant on Pelee Island, Ontario", 1952 (Box 129, Folder 8)
    - "The Arctic Barons", undated (Box 129, Folder 9)
    - Bird Unit at Florida Centennial Parade, January 1925 (Box 129, Folder 10)
    - "Recovery of Acorns in the European Jay", 1968 (Box 129, Folder 11)
    - Boston Transcripts - 7 Reprints, 1925 (Box 129, Folder 12)
    - "Putting up Bird Boxes", 1908 (Box 129, Folder 13)
    - "Birds and Some Human Diseases", Jan-58 (Box 129, Folder 14)
    - "Auditory Responses of Starlings, English Sparrows, and Domestic Pigeons", March 1939 (Box 129, Folder 15)
    - Bird Voices in the Southland", February 1936 (Box 129, Folder 16)
    - "Hunting with a Sound Camera", 1933 (Box 129, Folder 17)
    - "A method for the Intensive Study of Bird Songs", January 1935 (Box 129, Folder 18)
    - "Progress in Recording Voices of American Birds", 1938 (Box 129, Folder 19)
    - "The Range of Hearing Canaries", 1939 (Box 129, Folder 20)
    - "Recording Sounds of Wild Birds", Oct-32 (Box 129, Folder 21)
    - "The Uses of Bird Sound Photography", 1936 (Box 129, Folder 22)
    - "Vibration Frequencies of Passerine Bird Song", 1938 (Box 129, Folder 23)
    - "Why Bird Song Cannot be Described Adequately", 1937 (Box 129, Folder 24)
    - "Cruelty and Fur", 1927 (Box 129, Folder 25)
    - "The Birds of Churchill", 1931 (Box 129, Folder 26)
    - "The Feeding Range of Certain Birds", 1927 (Box 129, Folder 27)
    - Fuertes and Audubon - A Comparison of the Work and Personalities of the World's Greatest Bird Artists", 1937 (Box 129, Folder 28)
    - "The Nesting Habit of the Crowned Hornbill", 1926 (Box 129, Folder 29)
    - "Nesting Habits of the Cedar Waxwing", 1936 (Box 129, Folder 30)
    - "Snare Notes of the Wild Birds", 1932 (Box 129, Folder 31)
    - "A Study of Wild and Hand Reared Killdeers", 1943 (Box 129, Folder 32)
    - "Adaptive Modifications and Ecological Isolating Mechanisms on the Thrush", 1956 (Box 129, Folder 33)
    - Brij Hypothesis as an Explanation for the Tropical Faunal Similarities between Western Ghats and the Eastern Himalayas, Assam, Burma and Malaya, 1952 (Box 129, Folder 34)
    - "Electrocution of Parakeets at Agra, India", 1954 (Box 129, Folder 35)
    - "Hibernation site of the Meadow Jumping Mouse", 1948 (Box 129, Folder 36)
    - "Hostile Behavior and Reproductive Isolating Mechanisms in the Avian Genera Catharus and Hylocichla", 1956 (Box 129, Folder 37)
    - "Hycichlid Thrushes in Captivity with Notes on Their Behavior", 1956 (Box 130, Folder 1)
    - "The Loss of Teeth in Birds", 1957 (Box 130, Folder 2)
    - "Relationships of the Thrush Genera Catharus and Hylocichla", 1956 (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - "Ruptured Heart in the Cardinal", 1955 (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - "Studies in Agapornis", 1958 (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - "Sanctuary on the Perkimen", 1951 (Box 130, Folder 6)
    - "Seeing Things?", 1925 (Box 130, Folder 7)
  - By Last Name of Author: E-H
    - "Bird Distribution along the Peace Slave and the Little Buffalo Rivers of Canada", 1948 (Box 130, Folder 8)
    - "Bird Notes from Western Kwangsi, China", 1957 (Box 130, Folder 9)
    - "A Life History Study of Seiurus Noveboracensis", 1957 (Box 130, Folder 10)
    - "Variation in Seiurus Noveboracensis", 1957 (Box 130, Folder 11)
    - "Wood Warblers Wintering in Cuba", 1953 (Box 130, Folder 12)
    - "The Mangrove Cuckoo in Interior Tamaulipas, Mexico", 1947 (Box 130, Folder 13)
    - "Notes on Birds of the Gomez Farias Region of Tamaulipas", 1948 (Box 130, Folder 14)
    - "An Unorthodox Nest of the Rose-throated Becard", 1947 (Box 130, Folder 15)
    - Hearing Ranges of Four Species of Birds", 1943 (Box 130, Folder 16)
    - "Roosts and Night Roosts of Birds", 1934 (Box 130, Folder 17)
    - "A Closer Look at the Killers", 1953 (Box 130, Folder 18)
    - "Fancy Pheasants and their Allies", 1901 (Box 130, Folder 19)
    - "The Smaller North American Mammals", 1918 (Box 130, Folder 20)
    - "Rose-throated Becard Nesting in the Chiricahua Mountains, Arizona, 1956 (Box 130, Folder 21)
    - "Charles Crawfoot Gorst", undated (Box 130, Folder 22)
    - Lawrence I. Grinnell - Three Articles, 1941-1949 (Box 130, Folder 23)
    - "Notes on Bird-life of Churchill, Manitoba, 1941 (Box 130, Folder 24)
    - "A Study of the Eastern Song Sparrow", 1931 (Box 130, Folder 25)
    - "Birds of the Ugaua Peninsula", 1958 (Box 130, Folder 26)
    - W.J. Hamilton - Two Articles, 1933 (Box 130, Folder 27)
    - "Longolius on Birds", 1958 (Box 130, Folder 28)
    - "Injury Feigning in the Willow Ptarmigan", 1950 (Box 130, Folder 29)
    - "Laughing Gull Nesting of Coast of Maine", 1949 (Box 130, Folder 30)
    - "Notes on Leach's Petrel", 1948 (Box 130, Folder 31)
    - "Double-occupied nests of the Eastern Cardinal", 1951 (Box 130, Folder 32)
    - "Ecological Relations of the Breeding Bird Population of the Desert Biome of Arizona", 1954 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - "Further Data on Removal and Re-population of the Breeding Birds of a Spruce-fir Forest Community", 1951 (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - "Management of an Artificial Marsh on Southern Ontario for Ducks and Muskrats", 1942 (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - "Notes on the Nesting Habits of the American Robin", 1942 (Box 131, Folder 4)
    - Studies on the Muscles of the Pelvic Appendage in Birds", 1937 (Box 131, Folder 5)
  - By Last Name of Author: J-P
    - "Population Structure in Salt Marsh Song Sparrows, Part I", 1956 (Box 131, Folder 6)
    - "Hunting Bird Songs with a Microphone", 1938 (Box 131, Folder 7)
    - "Music and Bird Song", 1955 (Box 131, Folder 8)
    - W.W. Kellogg Bird Sanctuary, 1931 (Box 131, Folder 9)
    - Biological Leaflets, 1942-1950 (Box 131, Folder 10)
    - "Variation of the External Ear-opening in the Strigidae", 1940 (Box 131, Folder 11)
    - A. Brooker Klugh - 3 Items, 1906-1919 (Box 131, Folder 12)